# Roston Sylvester Pereira

A versatile IT professional with 3+ years of experience in software development who can think out of the box and bring a diverse skill set and creative drive to software application development. Strong experience in object-oriented design with attention to detail. Supportive and enthusiastic team player dedicated to streamlining processes and efficiently resolving project issues.

Address: Mumbai, INDIA

Phone: (+91) 908 296 3209

E-mail: rostonpereira17@gmail.com

Website: https://rostonpereira.github.io

Express Entry No: E001044278

#### SKILLS:

## ❖ PERSONAL TRAITS:

• Research-Driven | Self Motivated | Team Performer | Meticulous

#### ❖ PRACTICAL SKILLS:

ASP.NET | ASP.NET MVC 5 | C#.NET | C++ | Android | HTML 5 | CSS 3 | JavaScript | Bootstrap 4 | SQL Server 2014 | MySQL | SDLC.

PASSIONATE
SELF-MOTIVATED
TEAM-PERFORMER
RESEARCH-DRIVEN

#### WORK EXPERIENCE:

Position: Senior Executive January 2017 to Present

Employer: Reliance Life Sciences Pvt. Ltd. - Navi Mumbai, India.

- Successfully designed and developed ASP.NET applications as per stakeholder requirements.
- Responsible for modifying and maintaining existing ASP.NET and Java applications as per stakeholder requirement.
- Responsible for development, validation, and testing of software as per 21 CFR Part 11 standards.
- Collaborate closely with stakeholders for requirement gathering and documentation.
- Coordinating with vendors and stakeholders to successfully implement third-party applications.
- Providing functional and administrative support for software applications.
- Conduct seminars, journal clubs, and training of software applications for business users.

Position: Software Development Engineer

February 2015 to January 2017

Employer: RNM Moving Pictures Pvt. Ltd. - Mumbai, India.

- Successfully designed and implemented the website for RNM Moving Pictures using HTML 5, CSS 3, jQuery, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.
- Spearheaded a multi-functional team of Software Engineers, Graphic Designers, and Video Editors to develop the platform 'Dance with Madhuri' (DWM).
- Successfully developed and maintained the android app for DWM.

#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

- Successfully developed and implemented an analytics dashboard of DWM platform using Java, and by
  integrating data from different sources like Google Analytics, Flurry, Bitgravity, Google play developer
  console, and iTunes connect.
- Successfully managed and maintained the database (i.e. MongoDB database) of DWM platform.
- Managed and maintained the DWM platform and its content on Amazon Web Services.

#### **EDUCATION:**

## • Master Of Science (MSc): Advanced Computer Science

2014

Department of Computer Science and Electronic Engineering | University of Essex, UK

## • Bachelors Of Science (BSc): Information Technology

2013

St Andrew's college of Arts, Science and Commerce | University of Mumbai, INDIA

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

## Vintage Football Club

2018

 Currently working on a project to create a website for a football club, using ASP.NET MVC 5, MySQL, and Amazon Web Services.

## Checkers Game | University of Essex

2014

- Led the team and managed the documentation of SDLC.
- Collaborated with team members to develop the UI of the game, using Java.

## Who wants to be a Millionaire | University of Essex

2013 - 2014

Successfully built an android app based on the TV game show "Who wants to be a Millionaire".

#### R-RunapP | University of Essex

2013 - 2014

Successfully devised and created a fitness app that helps people stay fit, by measuring the calories burned and
motivating them. The app also consisted of some inbuilt features like GPS navigation, Music player, and distress
button.

## Volcania Automobiles | St Andrew's college of Arts, Science and Commerce

2011

Successfully designed and implemented a website for automobile dealer, using ASP.NET and SQL Server 2008.

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

## Student Representative | University of Essex

2013 - 2014

- As a student representative I attended staff-student liaison committee meetings.
- Raised academic issues concerning the students.

## Student Switch off Ambassador | University of Essex

2013 - 2014

Created awareness on optimum use of resources like electricity, among university students.

## Volunteer | University of Essex

2013 - 2014

Created awareness about clean and healthy environment, among school students.

## Volunteer | Garbage concern NGO

2011

- Organised a clean-up drive campaign, along with an NGO.
- Scripted and acted in a play that conveyed the message of a clean and healthy environment.